## SHIVAM PANDEY

8454038839 • shivampandey2903@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/shivam-pandey-a99296213 •

ClickMe=>"My Portfolio"—- "Socials"—-"Github"—-"Leetcode"

#### **SUMMARY**

Computer Science student with experience in Full Stack MERN development, Blockchain developer and Data Science role. I had developed complex web applications that are both functional and aesthetically pleasing. I am confident in my ability to succeed any development role.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **B.Tech, Computer Science Engineering**

Graduating May 2024

University of Mumbai,

8.7 CGPA

Vidyavardhini College, Vasai

Relevant coursework: System Design OOPS DSA, Operating System Computer Networks SDLC

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Web development:** React JS, Next JS,Node JS,Javascript,CSS **Block Chain Development:** Solidity, Truffle, Ganache, Web3 JS

**Programming:** Python, C, C++ **Database:** MongoDB, MySql

Tools: VsCode, Remix IDE, MetaMask, Github

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Social Summer of Code (SSOC 23), Hack2skill: Contributor

June 2023 - Aug 2023

- Contributed as well as added my own project FIR system on the blockchain while collaborating with the team.
- Expanded my network and contributed to meaningful projects that impact the broader developer ecosystem.

#### Codesoft, IT, Consulting: Data Science Intern

June 2023 - July 2023

- Used statistical models to analyze,preprocess,train dataset .(Numpy,Pandas,Matplotlib,Scikit-learn,GCollab)
- · Collaborated with a talented team of data scientists.

#### **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

#### **Decentralized Complain Registration system**

May 2023-present

Collaborated in a team of three to design a Fir System on Blockchain.

- Enhanced security, fosters decentralization, ensures immutability of records, and provides transparency.
- Making a great solution for maintaining a trusty tamper-resistant system for registering and managing complaints.

Fill 2022

Build a Perfect Gym Companion website using various Apis.

Ensured team compliance to Design Control Procedures according to Code of Federal Regulations (CFR)

# Algorithm Visualizer Led team of three to design and develop an Algorithm Visualizer

Spring 2022

- Allows users to interact with mind-blowing visualizations and animation.
- Can control the animation speed, pause or resume the execution, serves as an Educational tool
- Implemented all types of Sorting algorithms, N Queen, Dfs Bfs A\*, Binary tree, Path Finding.

#### **ACTIVITIES**

### BitByte Go(Vcet)

Dec 2022- Present

Multiple leadership roles

Organized events and designed contests to encourage students in competitive programming

#### Airnova(Vcet)

Dec 2020- May 2022

Multiple roles

• Trained and worked on Ai model for Gesture control Drone using open cv.